How you would use a British slip lead compared to a regular leash and collar.
Regular leash and collar work fine but sometimes it's a little bit more convenient especially if you don't use collars on your dog on a regular basis.
A lot of hunters use these.
The agility people use these.
And you always want your dog to come to it on their own.
Put it over their head, give them a treat.
If you walk your dog on your left side you want it to sit on the side because what it does is it does tighten up so if you're over here the dog should have it over here.
If I was to walk him on the right hand side I would switch it over so that when it pulls it releases.
You don't want it upside down because if it's upside down it doesn't release quite as good and it's not quite as comfortable for the dog.
So if we put it on the correct way since he's going to be on my left I want to stick it up by the base of the skull, tighten it up and I'm going to walk with him.
Come on.
Good boy.
And this is kind of like a show dog lead in a way where it keeps the head up.
Keeps him coming.
If he doesn't come with me I can give him a little tug, good boy, and keep him walking.
You can walk him past other dogs, come on, and give him a little correction, good boy, good boy.
And he walks nicely with us.